Guide to the M. B. Spillard Photograph Collection circa 1910 - 1916
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
M. B. Spillard Photograph Collection
circa 1910 - 1916
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu
P 163
Spillard, M. B.
0.01 cubic foot, including 16 photographs 1 box
The M. B. Spillard Photograph Collection consists of photographic postcards of Oregon Agricultural College buildings and campus views in the early 1910s.
The M.B. Spillard Photograph Collection consists of photographic postcards of Oregon Agricultural College (OAC) buildings and campus views. The collection also includes images of a football game between OAC and the University of Oregon and a freshman football team. Of note is a photographic postcard of the first train from North Bend to Eugene with a message from Walker B. to the members of Phi Delta Sigma fraternity that was sent in May 1916.
The collection includes photographic postcards published by the Pacific Photo Company of Salem, Oregon, and the Pacific Novelty Company of San Francisco.
Collection is open for research.
This collection is arranged in one series: I. Photographs, circa 1910 - 1916.
The photographs were received by the University Archives in the 1970s.
The Special Collections & Archives Research Center holdings include many collections with photographic postcards from the early 20th century. Of special note are the Pacific Photo Company Postcards (P 023) and the Roland G. Holmes Collection of Oregon and Washington Postcards (P 283). Numerous collections held by the Center include photographs of campus buildings and views.
Oregon Agricultural College--Buildings.; Oregon Agricultural College--Students.; Pacific Novelty Co.; Pacific Photo Company (Salem, Or.)
College buildings--Oregon--Corvallis.; Football players--Oregon--Corvallis.
Photographic postcards.
Oregon; Corvallis; Colleges and Universities; Photographs; Sports and Recreation
- Photographs, circa 1910 - 1916; Series I
  Series I consists of photographic postcards of Oregon Agricultural College buildings and campus views.
  - First train from North Bend to Eugene, 1916; P163:01 (Box 1)
  - Freshman Football Team, circa 1915; P163:02 (Box 1)
  - Rooters at University of Oregon versus Oregon Agricultural College football game, circa 1915; P163:03 (Box 1)
  - Armory, circa 1910; P163:05-P163:06 (Box 1)
    McAlexander Fieldhouse.
  - Campus scene, circa 1910; P163:07 (Box 1)
    View to south of Armory (McAlexander Fieldhouse) and Gymnasium (Valley Gymnastics Center).
  - Arms room in the Armory, circa 1910; P163:08 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture Hall and the bandstand, circa 1912; P163:09 (Box 1)
    Strand Agriculture Hall
  - Men's Gymnasium, circa 1910; P163:10 (Box 1)
    Langton Hall
  - Dairy Building, circa 1912; P163:11 (Box 1)
    Gilkey Hall
  - OAC greenhouses, circa 1910; P163:12 (Box 1)
  - Farm Mechanics building, circa 1912; P163:13 (Box 1)
    Gilmore Hall
  - Campus scene, circa 1912; P163:14 (Box 1)
    Includes Benton Hall in foreground and Strand Agriculture Hall and Gilkey Hall in the background. Bicycle leaning against the exterior wall of Benton Hall.
  - Campus scene, circa 1910; P163:15 (Box 1)
    View to the south from the roof of Benton Hall includes Furman Hall, the Gladys Valley Gymnastics Center, McAlexander Fieldhouse, and campus walkways.
  - Campus view, circa 1912; P163:16 (Box 1)
    View toward lower campus from the rooftop of a building on Jefferson Avenue.
  - The Avonlea, circa 1910; P163:17 (Box 1)
    Men standing on porch roof.